所以我们离开了
so we left
你在结尾处有点悬崖峭壁
you with a bit of a cliff hanger at the end of
最后一个模块
the last module
是否在我们的野生动物保护区发现了大脚怪
has bigfoot been spotted at our wildlife refuge or not
不幸的是，没有
well unfortunately no it hasn't been
在任一情况下
in either case
当我们的服务器中的路由不匹配时会发生什么
what happens when a route doesn't match in our server
好
well
我们还应该处理带参数的请求
we should also handle requests that take parameters
我们决定建立网络的原因之一
one of the reasons we decided to build a web
本课程中的服务器
server in this course
是否提供了不同的学习场景
is it presents different scenarios to learn
灵药的不同特点
different features of elixir
所以让我们看看更多的模式匹配技术
so let's look at some more pattern matching techniques
因为它们是构建 elixir 应用程序的核心
as they're central to building elixir apps
所以这是我们到目前为止定义的两条路线
so here are the two routes we have defined so far
一种用于野生动物
one for wild things
1 4 只熊和这些
1 4 bears and these
是我们的应用程序知道的两个资源
are the two resources that our application knows about
但对于其他一切
but for everything else
对于我们收到的任何其他请求
for any other requests that we get
我们要发送一个四行四响应
we want to send a four row four response
说可以找到资源
saying that the resource can be found
为此，我们将定义一条捕获所有路线
and to do that we'll define a catch all route
我就在这里做
I'm just going to do it right up here
所以是路线它会采取我们的对话地图
so be route it's going to take our conversation map
然后而不是使用像 get 这样的文字字符串
and then instead of using a literal string like get
我只是要使用方法
I'm just going to use method
这是一个将得到的变量
that's a variable that will get
匹配传入的任何参数
matched to whatever argument is passed in
作为那里的第二个论点
as the second argument there
然后以同样的方式我们想要匹配任何路径
and then in the same way we want to match any path
所以我将在那里使用可变路径
so I'm just going to use a variable path there
这将匹配任何东西
which will match anything
然后在里面
and then inside of here
好吧，我们只是返回
well we just return
更新的对话地图，所以 co 和 v
a updated conversation map so co and v
我们的竖线，然后是我们的响应体
our vertical bar and then our response body
在这种情况下会说
in this case is going to say
不
no
这里的路径
path here
所以不管第三个论点是什么
so whatever the third argument is that gets past
这个函数将被绑定
this function is going to get bound
到我们可以使用的变量路径
to the variable path which we can use
函数体内
inside of the function body
如果我们现在运行它
and if we run this right now
我们会收到一条警告说没有使用该方法
we'll get a warning saying that method wasn't used
函数体内
inside of the function body
所以我们可以忽略那个警告
so we can just ignore that warning
加下划线
by putting an underscore
在那个变量之前
before that variable
如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
if we save that away and run it
好吧，我们在底部没有看到大脚怪，但是
well we see no bigfoot here at the bottom but
这里没有熊
no bears here
这里没有野东西
no wild things here
一切都匹配这个
everything is matching this
返回的路线在这里知道什么
route that's returning know whatever here
如果我们走到顶部，我们会看到这个警告
if we go to the top we see we get this warning
此功能爪无法匹配
this function claws cannot match
因为以前的爪子在线
because of previous claws online
26 总是匹配
26 always matches
那是因为
and that's because
elixir 尝试匹配来自的函数子句
elixir tries to match function clauses from
从上到下
top to bottom
按照文件中指定的顺序
in the order they're specified in the file
没错，我们可以找到所有路线
that's right and we have our catch all route to find
在我们的其他路线之上，我们在这里使用了变量
above our other routes and we used variables here
所以传入的任何值都是第二个参数
so whatever value is passed in is the second argument
它会自动匹配
it's going to match automatically
到那个可变方法
to that variable method
或者它将绑定该值
or it's going to bind that value
一样的方法
the same way
第三个参数值将绑定到路径
the third argument value is going to be bound to path
所以这将匹配任何方法和路径
so this is going to match any method and path
并且因为它匹配所有请求
and because it matches all requests it's going to
我们尝试处理的每个请求都会被调用
get called for every request that we try to handle
所以任何路线都可以找到
so any routes to find
低于这个永远不会被考虑
below this are never going to be considered
所以我们只希望调用这个函数
so we only want this function to be called
如果没有其他子句匹配
if no other clauses match
换句话说，它是默认函数子句
in other words it's the default function clause
所以我们需要最后定义它
so we need to define it last
是的，我们将把它从顶部取下来
yeah we'll just take it off the top here
把它放在我们其他路线的下面
put it down below our other routes
如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
and if we save that away and run it
好吧，我们这里没有大脚怪，这就是我们所期望的
well we get no bigfoot here that's what we expected
但我们所有的
but all of our
其他请求正在按我们的预期处理
other requests are getting handled as we would expect
我们应该提到的另一件事
one other thing we should mention
对函数子句进行分组不仅有帮助
not only is it helpful to group the function clauses
在一起，这样您就可以轻松查看订单
together so you can easily see the order
但是如果您将所有路线从组中移出
but if you move the catch all route out of the group
假设我们将其移至格式响应下方
say we move it below format response
然后我们运行得很好
and then we run it well
如果我们向上滚动
if we scroll up
我们会看到一个警告
we'll see a warning
这表示它们需要组合在一起
that says they need to be grouped together
所以在继续之前，我们将撤消它
so before moving on we'll just undo that
所以我们的响应正文正在更新
so our response body is being updated
但是 200 ok 是我们的状态
but the 200 ok is our status
那真的不正确
well that really isn't correct
真的应该是四四
it really should be a four or four
但现在它在我们的响应字符串中被硬覆盖
but right now it's hard coated in our response string
所以要让它更有活力
so to make this more dynamic
我们需要能够退出
we need to be able to pull out
我们对话地图中的状态码
the status code from our conversation map
然后我们可以在这里插值
and then we can just interpolate that down here
所以我们需要添加一个状态字段到
so we need to add a status field to the
对话地图，就在顶部
conversation map and that's just up here at the top
我要把这些分开
I'm going to split these out
成多行
into multiple line
只是为了让它更容易阅读
just to make it a little bit easier to read
我们就会有感觉
and we'll just have a feel
称为状态，我们最初将其设置为 nil
called status and we'll set it to nil initially
然后在我们的捕获所有路线底部
then down in our catch all route which is at the bottom
在这里我们可以将状态设置为四或四
here we can set the status to four or four
这只是证明
and this just demonstrates
你可以更新
you can update
使用语法的地图中的多个字段
multiple fields in a map using the syntax
记住你会得到一个
and just remember you're going to get back a
这张地图的新副本
new copy of this map
然后我们还需要在这里设置一个状态
and then we also need to set a status here
这将是成功的状态 200
this is going to be status 200 that was successful
这也将是状态 200
as well this is going to be status 200
然后最后
and then finally
我们可以插值而不是硬编码的 200
we can interpolate that instead of a hard coded 200
在这里，我们将只使用
here we'll just use
通讯状态
com status
现在状态码有相应的原因短语
now status codes have a corresponding reason phrase
例如 200 是可以的
for example 200 is okay
但是四四个没有找到
but four or four is not found
所以这样做
so to do that
我们需要将状态码映射到它们的
we need a mapping of the status codes to their
相应的原因
corresponding reason
并快速解决这个问题
and to make quick work of this
我这里有一个功能
I have a function here
我们可以粘贴进去
that we can just paste in to do this
现在有时你想定义
now sometimes you want to define
可以的私有函数
private functions that can
只能在模块内调用
only be called within the module
它们被定义在
that they're defined in
为此，您使用 def 而不是 def
and to do that you use def instead of def
所以只是为了证明
so just to demonstrate that
我们已设置此状态原因
we've set this status reason
成为一个私人功能，因此它不能
to be a private function and as such it can't
在模块外调用
be called outside the module
它需要一个参数
and it takes a single argument the code
然后在函数体内
and then inside of the function body
我们有一张地图
we have a map
在这种特殊情况下
in this particular case
我们正在尝试将状态代码映射到他们的原因
we're trying to map status codes to their reasons
所以这张地图中的键是数字
and so the keys in this map are numbers
它们不是原子
they're not atoms
那么我们需要使用这个 a 来
then as such we need to use this a to
将键与值联系起来
tie the key to the value
这会很熟悉
and this will be familiar
如果你是一名 ruby 程序员，因为你使用
if you are a ruby programmer because you use
ruby 哈希中的类似箭头语法
similar arrow syntax in ruby hashes
所以给了一个代码
so given a code
我们可以使用方括号语法
we can use a square bracket syntax
访问与该代码关联的值
to access the value that's associated with that code
给定这个函数，我们可以插值
given this function then we can interpolate
状态原因而不是硬编码
the status reason instead of the hardcoded
好吧，我们只是插值
okay we just interpolate
状态原因
status reason
并以 cv status 的状态传递它
and pass it in the status which is cv status
保存并运行它
save that away and run it
现在没有大脚怪
now for no bigfoot
在这里我们看到它是一个四或四个没有找到
here we see it's a four or four not found
但对于其他一切，它应该是 200 好的
but for everything else it should be a 200 ok
所以让我们创建一个新请求
so let's create a new request
让我们接受熊的请求
let's take the request for bears
并将其更改为熊一
and change it to bears one
这样我们就可以通过它的 id 得到一个特定的熊
that way we can get a specific bear by its id
熊一熊二熊三随便
bear one bear two bear three whatever
现在如果我们把它保存起来并在我们没有得到的时候运行它
now if we save that away and we run it while we get no
这里有一个
bears one here
它被我们的全部路线所接收
and it's getting picked up by our catch all route
处理这个
to handle this
我们需要定义一个路由函数子句
we're going to need to define a route function clause
与路径匹配
that matches the path with
一开始就熊
bears at the beginning
然后是最后的任何数字
and then any number at the end
有一个很酷的方法可以做到这一点
and there's a really cool way to do this
并设置它
and to set it up
我要跳进我
I'm going to jump into I
x 所以假设我们有绳子熊
x so let's say we have the string bears
我们想连接
and we want to concatenate
该字符串末尾的 No.1
the No.1 to the end of that string
在长生不老药中，字符串是二进制文件
well in elixir strings are binaries
并连接二进制文件
and to concatenate binaries
我们使用小于大于运算符
we use the less than greater than operator
然后我只给它一个字符串
and then I just give it the string one
我们拿回斜线熊一个
we get back slash bears one
但很酷的是我们也可以使用
but what's cool is we can also use
小于
the less than
大于运算符
greater than operator
在模式匹配中匹配字符串的开头
to match the beginning of a string in a pattern match
所以让我们替换这个
so let's just replace this one
带有变量 id
with a variable id
然后我们将使用匹配运算符和
and then we'll use the match operator and
看看是否匹配
see if that matches
熊
bears
一并且它做了它所做的就是它绑定了值一
one and it does what it did is it bound the value one
到要制作的变量 id
to the variable id to make
此模式匹配右侧
this pattern match the right hand side
如果我们仔细观察 id 变量，它的值为 1
and if we look at the id variable well its value is one
所以它匹配字符串的开头
so it matched the beginning of the string
然后字符串的其余部分被绑定
and then the rest of the string was bound
到变量id
to the variable id
所以我们可以用它来定义一个新的
so we can use this to define a new
路由功能子句
route function clause
这将是一个获取请求
it's going to be a get request
然后我们要匹配一个以开头的字符串
and then we want to match a string beginning with
带有斜线，然后有一个 id
bears slash and then having an id after that
然后在函数体中
and then in the function body
我们将返回更新的对话地图
we'll return an updated conversation map
状态为 200
where the status is 200
和响应体
and the response body
是裸露的，然后我们可以使用
is bare and then we can use
像这样绑定到变量 id 的值
the value that's bound to the variable id like that
这是有效的，因为模式匹配适用
and this works because pattern matching applies
任何时候我们需要将值绑定到变量
anytime we need to bind values to variables
在这种情况下，当调用此函数时
in this case when this function is called
第三个论点
the third argument
将获得与此模式匹配的模式
is going to get pattern matched against this pattern
所以争论会像熊一样
so the argument will be like bears one
它匹配模式并且因为它匹配它绑定
it matches the pattern and because it matches it binds
价值一
the value one
to id 所以这与这些不同
to id so this is different from these
其他路由功能
other route functions
因为在这里我们只是匹配
because here we were just matching
文字字符串
literal strings
这里我们实际上在模式中有一个变量
here we actually have a variable in the pattern
我们匹配的
that we match against
然后我们可以使用
and then we can use
函数体内的那个变量
that variable inside of the function body
现在如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
now if we save this away and run it
好吧，我们得到了 200 ok 的请求
well we get 200 ok for that request
它只是说熊一
and it just says bear one
想象所有
imagine all the
如果我们有会参观我们野生动物保护区的人
people who would visit our wildlife refuge if we had
大脚怪
a bigfoot
我们可以为大脚怪自拍收取一笔巨款
we could charge a fortune for selfies with bigfoot